This work makes three contributions.
First,
it is the first theoretical characterization of how
to train a Transformer that keeps
both nonlinear self-attention and a nonlinear MLP,
and it proves the trained model generalizes in
context to unseen tasks,
quantifying the required amount of data, number of
iterations, and context length.
Second, it expands our understanding of the
mechanism of in-context learning,
showing how the attention layer and the MLP layer
cooperate to make correct predictions.
Third,
it provides the first theoretical analysis of
magnitude-based pruning for in-context learning,
proving that removing low-magnitude neurons is
essentially harmless.